propertyindex.com 2012-10-27

# About Property Index | PropertyIndex.com

PropertyIndex.com Privacy Policy. Effective Date: 8th October 2008

## 1\. Who are we?

1.1 We are PropertyIndex.com Ltd, an English registered company (number 05729141). Our registered office is 1 Franchise Street, Kidderminster, Worcester, DY11 6RE. Our main trading address is The Forge, Forge Mews, 14-16 Church Street, Rickmansworth, Hertfordshire. WD3 1DH.

1.2 We own and operate this site.

1.3 Our contact details are in the "contact us" section on our site. Please get in touch if you have any questions or feedback about this policy. We’d be delighted to help.

## 2\. What’s the point of this policy?

2.1 The idea is that we tell you how we deal your "personal data" (This is the technical term for information about any identified or identifiable living person). Please read on to find out what kinds personal data we collect, how we use and protect it, to whom we disclose it and how you can access and rectify it.

2.2 We want you to feel comfortable with what we do. So much so that we don’t agree to you using our site unless you are completely happy with this policy. If you do use our site, we’ll assume that you do accept the policy.

## 3\. Might the policy change?

3.1 It may well do and so you should check it whenever you visit our site. We’ll assume you agree to the revised policy if you use the site after the effective date shown at the top of the policy. We will post any changes at least 14 days before they become effective.

## 4\. What personal or other data do we collect?

4.1 We collect and store the information which you enter into forms on our site - such as your name, address, email address, phone number, country, property requirements, site preferences and so on - or when communicating with us by email or by telephone or in some other way.

4.2 We may receive and store certain information automatically when you interact with us. Examples include the internet protocol (IP) address used to connect your computer to the internet, connection information such as browser type and version, your operating system and platform, a unique reference number linked to the data you enter on our system, login details, the full URL clickstream to, through and from our site (including date and time), cookie number, activity on our website including the pages you visited and searches you made.

## 5\. What about cookies?

5.1 You should be aware that by using the site, information and data may be automatically collected through the use of cookies. "Cookies" are small text files that store basic information that a website can use to recognise repeat site visits and, as an example, recall your name if this has been previously supplied. We may use this information (and share it with third party business partners) to observe your internet use and to compile data in order to improve the site, target advertising and assess general effectiveness of such advertising.

5.2 Cookies do not attach to your system or damage your files. If you do not want information to be collected through the use of cookies, there is a simple procedure in most browsers that allows you to deny or accept cookies. Note, however, that "personalised" services may be affected if the cookies option is disabled. To view your security settings in Internet Explorer, access the Internet Options within the tools menu in your browser and select the Privacy tab to choose a privacy setting for the internet zone you are in. For further information on cookies and cookie settings, including how to delete cookies, visit www.allaboutcookies.org.

5.3 Session cookies are temporary cookies that remain in the cookie file of your browser until you leave the site. We use session cookies to remember you as you move from page to page, so you do not need to continually log in.

5.4 Persistent cookies stay in the cookie file of your browser for longer (though how long will depend on the lifetime of the specific cookie). We use persistent cookies when you revisit the website so that you do not need to log in again (if you so request); track your country to enable us to provide country-specific content, track whether you entered our site from a link on a site of one of our business partners, avoid showing you the same advert repeatedly, to display adverts or other content tailored to your preferences.

## 6\. How do we use your personal data?

6.1 We use your personal data to provide our services e.g. send service-related messages (such as new property alerts, newsletters, customer questionnaires), process payments and/or fulfil orders.

6.2 If you make an enquiry on or via our site, as part of our service we may telephone you to check that you are satisfied with the outcome and, if not, to enquire whether you would like your property requirements and contact details to be passed to other property owners or agents. If you tick the box saying you are interested in other properties, again as part of the service we may telephone you to see if you would like your requirements concerning those other properties and your contact details to be passed to other property owners or agents.

6.3 We use your personal data to help us communicate with you effectively should you try to contact us via our site including verification of any claims you may make.

6.4 If you have agreed on our site, we may use your personal data to send you promotional emails (or other communications) with details of our or third party goods or services which may be of interest to you including information about special offers or promotions.

6.5 We may use cookies, IP addresses or personal data to recognize you when you visit or return to our site so we can show you adverts or other content tailored to your preferences, to track anonymised traffic and usage patterns, to prevent or detect fraud or abuses or to help us improve our site.

6.6 We may access, remove, alter or store or otherwise use any personal data if we think you have or may have breached our terms and conditions or to enforce our rights or protect the public or where if we are required to do so by law or appropriate authority.

## 7\. How do we protect personal data?

7.1 Security is a high priority. We take precautions to protect personal data from loss, misuse, unauthorised access or disclosure, alteration or destruction using the same safeguards as we use for our own proprietary information.

7.2 We maintain physical and procedural safeguards in connection with the collection, storage and disclosure of personal data.

7.3 Our banking partner uses 128 bit SSL technology to encrypt credit card transactions. Only the last four digits of your credit card number are revealed when confirming an order.

7.4 Don’t forget that email communications over the internet are not secure if they haven’t been encrypted. Your emails may pass through servers in a number of countries before they reach us. So we don’t accept responsibility for any unauthorised access or loss of personal data that stems from a cause beyond our control.

## 8\. To whom do we disclose personal data?

8.1 Payment details including credit card numbers are supplied direct to our banking partner. We do not store such information.

8.2 When you make a property enquiry via our site, we will disclose your name, phone number and email address (these are compulsory) plus whatever additional optional details you specify at the time of the enquiry to the relevant property owner, agent or developer.

8.3 So far as other properties are concerned, if you authorize us by telephone (see above) or if you use our Property Finder Service, we will supply your contact details and property requirements to carefully selected property owners or agents who will be responsible for contacting you direct.

8.4 We may allow access to your personal data by third parties who supply us with a service - for the purpose of their service only and in accordance with our instructions. Examples include website hosts and businesses which assist us in undertaking communications or monitoring our site.

8.5 If you have agreed on our site, we may provide your personal data to selected third parties so that they can send you emails (or other communications) with details of goods or services which may be of interest to you including information about special offers or promotions.

8.6 We may disclose personal data so far as reasonably necessary:

a) if we think you have or may have breached our terms and conditions or to enforce our rights or protect the public or where if we are required to do so by law or appropriate authority; or

b) in the case of an actual or proposed (including negotiations for a) sale or merger or business combination involving all of or the relevant part of our business.

8.7 We may share your information with any other companies within our group for the purposes stated in this privacy policy.

8.8 We will take reasonable steps to require that third parties to whom we transfer any personal data will agree to provide sufficient protection. We may store or transfer personal data outside the European Economic Area for the purposes stated in this policy.

## 9\. How can you access and rectify personal data?

9.1 You can access and rectify your personal data by contacting us via the "contact us" page on our website. We may charge an administration fee in line with data protection laws.

9.2 For information about your rights under UK data protection laws, see the website of the UK Information Commissioner at [www.ico.gov.uk](http://www.ico.gov.uk/).

Version: 2.0
